Committee of Correspondence Records, 1952-1989 (bulk 1952-1971)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. CORRESPONDENTS AND FIELD WORK
  - Regions: Europe
    - Country files
      - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (Box 32, Folder 35)
      - Yugoslavia
        - Correspondence, general (Box 33, Folder 1)
        - Dukanac, Spasenija (Box 33, Folder 2)
        - Janic, Nadezda (Box 33, Folder 3)
        - Pinterovic, Danica (Box 33, Folder 4)
        - Segan-Budimlic, Vera (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Regions: Latin America
    - General
      - Latin American program: correspondence, proposals, and travel reports, 1956-68, [see also Brazil] (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
      - Frances Foland, Field Consultant
        - Photos and miscellany (Box 33, Folder 8)
        - Correspondence and travel reports, 1962-68 (Box 33, Folder 9-10)
      - Sara Wacker, Field Consultant: correspondence and reports, 1966-68 (Box 33, Folder 11-12)
    - Country files
      - Argentina (Box 33, Folder 13-14)
      - Bolivia (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Brazil
        - Reports, 1956-65 (Box 34, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, general (Box 34, Folder 2-4)
        - Brasilia National Congress: "The Role of Women in Social Development" 1965
          - Correspondence and memos (Box 34, Folder 5)
          - Conference materials and reports (Box 34, Folder 6)
          - Subject files, participating organizations (in Portuguese) (Box 34, Folder 7)
        - Fortaleza Conference, 1966: planning materials and reports (Box 34, Folder 8)
        - Sao Paolo Seminar, 1965
          - Conference materials (Box 34, Folder 9-10)
          - Final report (Box 34, Folder 11)
        - Movimento Brasileiro de Correspondencia (Box 34, Folder 12)
      - Chile (Box 34, Folder 13)
      - Colombia (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Costa Rica (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Ecuador (Box 35, Folder 3)
      - El Salvador (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Guatemala (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Guyana (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Honduras (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Mexico (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Nicaragua (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Panama (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - Paraguay (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Peru
        - Correspondence, general (Box 35, Folder 12)
        - de Belaunde, Giesela (Box 35, Folder 13)
        - de Benavente, Haydee (Box 35, Folder 14)
        - Consejo Nacional de Menores (Box 35, Folder 15-16)
        - Gonzales, Celia Barrios (Box 36, Folder 1)
        - Movimento Civico Feminino del Peru (Box 36, Folder 2)
        - Porturas, Elisa Calmet (Box 36, Folder 3)
        - de Sagasti, Elsa (Box 36, Folder 4)
        - de Sanchez Pauli, Elena (Box 36, Folder 5)
        - de Santolalia, Irene Silva (Box 36, Folder 6)
        - Vasquez-Solis, Jennie (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Surinam (Box 36, Folder 8)
      - Uruguay
        - Correspondence, general (Box 36, Folder 9-10)
        - Abella, Vilma (Box 36, Folder 11)
        - Armand-Ugon, Silvia Tron (Box 36, Folder 12)
        - Atella, Maria Rosa (Box 36, Folder 13)
        - de Castleton, Lorraine (Box 36, Folder 14)
        - Haberli, Iris (Box 36, Folder 15)
        - Laguardia, Ana (Box 36, Folder 16)
        - Lopez, Celina Rolleri (Box 36, Folder 17)
        - de Lorenzo, E. (Box 36, Folder 18)
        - Pereyra, Gerarda Nelis Ayala (Box 36, Folder 19)
        - de Roper, Olga (Box 36, Folder 20)
        - de Viana, Celia Reyes (Box 37, Folder 1)
        - de Volpe, Olga (Box 37, Folder 2)
        - Young Women's Christian Association (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Venezuela
        - Correspondence, general (Box 37, Folder 4)
        - Amengual, Maria Carmen de Rodriguez (Box 37, Folder 5)
        - Boccalandro, A. (Box 37, Folder 6)
        - Castro, Iris (Box 37, Folder 7)
        - Morales, Lourdes (Box 37, Folder 8)
        - Paiz, Carmen Romero (Box 37, Folder 9)
        - de Phelps, Kath (Box 37, Folder 10)
        - Servico Social Internacional (Box 37, Folder 11)
        - United States Embassy (Box 37, Folder 12)
        - de Vallejo, Nery (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Regions: Middle East
    - Travel reports, general, 1958-64, [see also SERIES III. CONFERENCES, SEMINARS, AND WORKSHOPS: Iran, 1963] (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Country files
      - Aden Protectorate (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Egypt (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Iran (Box 38, Folder 4-5)
      - Iraq
        - Correspondence, general (Box 38, Folder 6)
        - Rasheed, Mrs. Guzine (workshop participant) (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Israel (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Jordan (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Kuwait (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Lebanon (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Saudi Arabia
        - Correspondence, general (Box 38, Folder 12)
        - Yassin, Mrs. Samira Kashoggi (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Syria
        - Correspondence, general (Box 38, Folder 14)
        - Correspondence with non-members (Box 38, Folder 15)
        - Ayoubi, Senie (Box 38, Folder 16)
        - Chaura, Kamar Kazoun (Box 38, Folder 17)
        - Chelot, Rita (Box 38, Folder 18)
        - Ibish, Ihsan (workshop participant) (Box 38, Folder 19)
        - Jabri, Atifa (workshop participant) (Box 39, Folder 1-2)
        - Jazairy, Amal (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - Katibi, Haifa Arabi (Box 39, Folder 4)
        - Mahmoud, Ihsan Mahmoudi (Box 39, Folder 5)
        - Pusha, Dr. Zahida Homid (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Trucial States (Box 39, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, general (Box 39, Folder 8-9)
      - Catholic Women's League of Canada (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Federated Women's Institutes of Canada (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Royal Bank of Canada (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - United States Embassy (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Young Women's Christian Association (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - United States
      - Government agencies
        - General (Box 39, Folder 15)
        - Congress (House and Senate) (Box 39, Folder 16)
        - Agency for International Development (Box 39, Folder 17)
        - Department of Agriculture (Box 39, Folder 18)
        - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (Box 39, Folder 19)
        - Department of Labor (Box 39, Folder 20)
        - Department of State (Box 39, Folder 21-23)
        - United States Information Agency (Box 39, Folder 24-25)
      - Individuals, A
        - General (Box 39, Folder 26)
        - Adams, Ruth (Box 39, Folder 27)
        - Arter, Rhetta (Research and Action Association) (Box 39, Folder 28)
      - Organizations, A
        - Aa-Al (Box 39, Folder 29)
        - Adult Education Association of the U.S.A. (Box 39, Folder 30)
        - African-American Institute (Box 39, Folder 1)
        - American A-American F (Box 39, Folder 2)
        - American Association of University Women (Box 39, Folder 3)
        - American Friends of the Middle East (Box 39, Folder 4)
        - American Friends Service Committee (Box 39, Folder 5)
        - American Home Economics Association (Box 39, Folder 6)
        - American Labor Education Service (Box 39, Folder 7)
        - American I-American Women (Box 39, Folder 8)
        - An-Az (Box 39, Folder 9)
        - Asia Foundation (California) (Box 39, Folder 10)
        - Asia Society (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - B
        - Ba-Be (Box 40, Folder 12)
        - Baum, Serena (Box 40, Folder 13)
        - Behrens, Beatrice (Box 40, Folder 14)
        - Bi-Bo (Box 40, Folder 15)
        - Bijur, Marion (Box 40, Folder 16)
        - Board of Education, City of New York (Box 40, Folder 17)
        - Boulding, Elise (Box 40, Folder 18)
        - Br-By (Box 40, Folder 19)
      - C
        - Ca-Ch (Box 40, Folder 20)
        - Campbell, Dr. Persia (Box 40, Folder 21)
        - Castel, Helene (Box 40, Folder 22)
        - Christian Science Monitor (Box 40, Folder 23)
        - Ci-Cop (Box 40, Folder 24)
        - Clark, Mrs. Forrest (Box 40, Folder 25)
        - Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS) (Box 40, Folder 26)
        - Committee of Correspondence (Cambridge) (Box 40, Folder 27)
        - Cooperative League of the U.S.A. (Box 40, Folder 28)
        - Cor-Cu (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - D
        - General (Box 41, Folder 2)
        - Dybwad, Rosemary (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - E-F (Box 41, Folder 4-5)
      - G
        - General (Box 41, Folder 6)
        - Gerson, Mary-Joan (Box 41, Folder 7)
        - Giles, Dr. Harry (Box 41, Folder 8)
        - Girl Scouts (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - H
        - Ha (Box 41, Folder 10)
        - Heffelfinger, Elizabeth (Box 41, Folder 11)
        - He-Hi (Box 41, Folder 12)
        - Ho (Box 41, Folder 13)
        - Horton, Mildred (Box 41, Folder 14)
        - Hu-Hz (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - I (Box 41, Folder 16)
      - J
        - General (Box 42, Folder 1)
        - Jones, Joan (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - K (Box 42, Folder 3-4)
      - L
        - La-Lef (Box 42, Folder 5)
        - Ladies Home Journal (Box 42, Folder 6)
        - Lane Bryant (Box 42, Folder 7)
        - Latimer, Mrs. F.P., Jr. (Box 42, Folder 8)
        - Leg-Lo (Box 42, Folder 9)
        - Letters Abroad (Marsh, Mrs. William) (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - M
        - Ma (Box 42, Folder 11)
        - Mc (Box 42, Folder 12)
        - Me-Mi (Box 42, Folder 13)
        - Miller, Frieda (Box 42, Folder 14)
        - Mo-Mz (Box 42, Folder 15)
      - N
        - Na (Box 42, Folder 16)
        - National Council of Women (Box 42, Folder 17)
        - Ne-Nz (Box 42, Folder 18)
      - O
        - Correspondence, general (Box 43, Folder 1)
        - Overseas Education Fund of the League of Women Voters (Box 43)
          - Correspondence, general (Box 43, Folder 2-4)
          - Leadership Internships (Box 43, Folder 5)
      - P
        - Pa (Box 43, Folder 6)
        - Pe-Pz (Box 43, Folder 7)
        - Peterson, Esther (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - R
        - Correspondence, general (Box 43, Folder 9)
        - Racine, Gladys (Box 43, Folder 10)
        - Riddle, Katharine (Box 43, Folder 11)
      - S
        - Sa-Sc (Box 43, Folder 12)
        - Se-Sl (Box 43, Folder 13)
        - Sm-So (Box 43, Folder 14)
        - Smith College Library (Box 43, Folder 15)
        - Snyder, Margaret (Box 43, Folder 16)
        - Sp-Sz (Box 44, Folder 1)
      - T (Box 44, Folder 2-3)
      - U (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - W-Y (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A., National Board (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - Youth Leaders, Cleveland International Program for Youth (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Regions: Caribbean
    - Travel reports, general, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Country files
      - Cuba (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - Dominican Republic (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Haiti (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Jamaica (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - Puerto Rico (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Virgin Islands
        - Correspondence, general (Box 44, Folder 14)
        - Williams, Helen (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - West Indies
        - Correspondence, general (Box 44, Folder 16)
        - Correspondence, non-members (Box 44, Folder 17)
        - Blood, Enid (Box 44, Folder 18)
        - Clark, Ann (Box 44, Folder 19)
        - Daysh, Florence (Box 44, Folder 20)
        - Feliz, Ruby (Box 44, Folder 21)
        - Gairy, Cynthia (Box 44, Folder 22)
        - Hagley, Cynthia (Box 44, Folder 23)
        - Johnson, Doris (Box 44, Folder 24)
        - Lucas, Yvonne (Box 44, Folder 25)
        - Marshall, Mrs. V. (Box 44, Folder 26)
        - Martineau, Dorrie (Box 44, Folder 27)
        - Maughan, Thelma (Box 44, Folder 28)
        - Mayers, Stella (Box 44, Folder 29)
        - Peters, Winifred (Box 44, Folder 30)
        - Pressey, Mary (Box 44, Folder 31)
        - Protain, Gertrude (workshop participant): includes conference materials (Box 44, Folder 32-33)
        - Pujadas-McShine, Leonora (Box 44, Folder 34)
        - St. Lucia's Women's Association (Box 44, Folder 35)
        - United States Embassy and Information Service (Box 44, Folder 36)
        - Ward, Mrs. E.R.L. (Box 44, Folder 37)
        - Wyke, Mrs. David (Box 45, Folder 1)
        - Young Women's Christian Association of Grenada (Box 45, Folder 2)
        - Young Women's Christian Association of Trinidad (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Regions: South Pacific
    - Australia
      - Correspondence, general, A-Z (Box 45, Folder 4-5)
      - Hastie, C.I.M. (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Caroline Islands
      - Correspondence, general (Box 45, Folder 7)
      - Blailes, Margie (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Cook Islands (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Fiji (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Marshall Islands: Lanwi, Mrs. M. (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - New Guinea (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - New Zealand (Box 45, Folder 13-14)
    - Samoa
      - Larkin, Fanaafi (Box 45, Folder 15)
      - Tofata, Tina-Fau (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Solomon Islands: Pelham-Johnson, Mrs. M. (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Tonga (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Addresses, activities, and interests of individual women by country: two sets of card files, circa 1956-68
      - Aden Protectorate - El Salvador 1956-68 (Box 46)
      - Ethiopia - Jamaica 1956-68 (Box 47)
      - Japan - Peru 1956-68 (Box 48)
      - Philippines - United Kingdom 1956-68 (Box 49)
      - U.S.A. - Zambia 1956-68 (Box 50)
    - Orange
      - Aden - Central African Republic (Box 50)
      - Ceylon - Solomon Islands (Box 51)
      - South Africa - Zambia (Box 52)
- SERIES VI. PHOTOGRAPHS
  - Countries
    - Cambodia (Mrs. Pung Peng Cheng and Dr. Frederick Mangold), 1957; and Greece (Queen Frederika and Mrs. Papagou), 1953-54 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Indonesia (Mary Saleh), circa 1988; and Senegal (Madame Annette M'Baye), 1965 (Box 2)
    - U.S.A.: Julie Chamberlain d'Estournelles [Mrs. Paul Herzog] and Jean Picker, undated (Box 3)
  - Workshops and seminars
    - East African Women's Seminar: includes Priscilla Abawo, Mrs. William Attwood, Mrs. Alcott Deming, Margaret Kenyatta, Mildred Marcy, Charity Mwanuka, Maria Nyerere, Sarale Owens, Peg Schneider, and Margaret Snyder, 1960? (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Workshop ["Women's Opportunity in the New Decade," New York City, 1960?]: enlargements of photos by Alfred Wertheimer
      - ==Photographer's contract and list of photos, 1960, undated Individuals and groups of in New York, Washington, DC, and Connecticut: enlargements (includes women from Afghanistan, Burma, Grenada, India, Iran, Kenya, Samoa, Sierra Leone, South Africa, Sudan, Tanganyika, Uganda, and United States (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - Nos. 4449-4480 with captions (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - Nos. 4483-4526 with captions (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - Unnumbered, with captions (Box 3, Folder 8)
        - Unidentified (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Unidentified groups (includes Eleanor Roosevelt) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Mosaique de la Chebba," Tunisia (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Alison Raymond Lanier's photographs, various Asian countries: photocopies]: enlargements of photos by Alfred Wertheimer1961, undated (Box 12)
- SERIES VII. ORAL HISTORIES
  - Audiocassette tapes, 1987-88
    [originals restricted; researchers must request use copy]
    - Aghevli, Ezzat 1987-88 (Box 54)
    - Anderson, Constance (Box 54)
    - Bauman, Dorothy (2) (Box 54)
    - Crolius, Anne (2) (Box 54)
    - Fazelbhoy, Zarina (Box 54)
    - Harris, Rosalind (Box 54)
    - Lanier, Alison (2) (Box 54)
    - McKeever, Susan and Porter (2) (Box 54)
    - Picker, Jean and Harvey (2) (Box 54)
    - Wadsworth, Elizabeth (2) (Box 54)
  - Transcripts and biographical material, 1987-88
    - Index and releases (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Aghevli, Ezzart (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Anderson, Constance (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Bauman, Dorothy
      - Transcript (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - Biography, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - "Right or Wrong," 1974 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      - "31 Days in the U.S.S.R., 1959 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Crolius, Anne (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Fazelbhoy, Zarina (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Harris, Rosalind W. (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Lanier, Alison Raymond
      - Transcript (Box 55, Folder 11)
      - Biography, 1987 (Box 55, Folder 12)
      - "A Part of Something Bigger," undated (Box 55, Folder 13)
      - "Up Country" (Uganda), undated (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - McKeever, Susan (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - McKeever, Porter (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Picker, Jean and Harvey (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Wadsworth, Elizabeth (Box 55, Folder 18)
  - Individuals not interviewed
    - Benson, Lucy: Van Voris' notes from phone conversation, 1988 (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - Height, Dorothy: correspondence and clipping, 1988 (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - Saleh, Mary: correspondence and printed material, 1988 (Box 55, Folder 21)
    - Strauss, Anna Lord: clippings and interview, 1946-79 (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - Trott, Mary: notes, 1988 (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - The Committee of Correspondence: Women with a World View, Jacqueline Van Voris, 1989: 2 copies, one annotated (Box 55, Folder 24)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - Inscribed Books: Joan Merli, Raquel Forner, 1952; and Jose Hernandez, Martin Fierro, 1962 (Box 56)
  - Awards
    - United States Information Agency, 1954 Girl Scouts of the United States of America, 1962 (Box 56)
  - ==Scrapbook: Iran conference, 1963 (Box 57)